anshuldudeja.com 2012-12-18

# Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy for anshuldudeja.blogspot.com / www. anshuldudeja.com**

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at anshuldudeja@gmail.com. 

At anshuldudeja.blogspot.com/www.anshuldudeja.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by anshuldudeja.blogspot.com/www.anshuldudeja.com and how it is used. 

**Log Files**

Like many other Web sites, anshuldudeja.blogspot.com/www.anshuldudeja.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

We use a number of different cookies on our site. If you do not know what cookies are, or how to control or delete them, then we recommend you visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) for detailed guidance. ****  
**  
**  
**Currently we operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage.** If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site, or you should delete anshuldudeja.com/anshuldudeja.blogspot.com cookies having visited the site, or you should browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” for Internet Explorer, "Private Browsing" in Firefox and Safari etc.)   
** **   
anshuldudeja.com/anshuldudeja.blogspot.com does not use cookies via the Blogger-based markup of this site, or in posts and pages. However, third party vendors whose advertisements are placed on this website may use cookies or web beacons. Details of these vendors are provided below.

**Third Party Cookies, Advertiser Cookies and Web Beacons** ****

**DoubleClick DART Cookie from Google**

.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on anshuldudeja.blogspot.com/www.anshuldudeja.com

.:: Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to anshuldudeja.blogspot.com/www.anshuldudeja.com and other sites on the Internet. 

.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - [http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

**Google Adsense**  

This cookie is used by Google to report to us how the adverts shown on www.anshuldudeja.com / anshuldudeja.blogspot.com are performing. User data is all anonymous. 

You can find out more generally about Google and its policies and principles as regards advertising at [http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/)

**Google Analytics**

We use this to understand how the site is being used in order to improve the user experience. User data is all anonymous. 

You can find out more about Google’s position on privacy as regards its analytics service at [http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)

**Six Apart Media**

This web site participates in Six Apart Media, a comprehensive advertising program provided by Six Apart Ltd. for publishers all across the Web. This section of our privacy policy describes how Six Apart Ltd. and the third party advertising networks and advertisers that display advertisements through Six Apart Media (collectively, "Advertisers") collect, use, store and disclose data from visitors to this Web site. A "cookie" is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a Web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies can be used to target advertisements relevant to your interests, based on your visits to different Web sites, to provide traffic measurement and other analytics and to conduct research. A "Web beacon" is an electronic file on a Web page that allows a Web site to count users who have visited that page, to access certain cookies and to provide auditing, research and reporting for advertisers. When your browser requests a page that displays advertising from one of the Advertisers, the Advertiser may view, edit or set its own cookie through your browser. In addition, the Advertiser may place its own Web beacon in the page, which may be triggered by your browser's request. **Advertiser Privacy Policies** If you would like to contact the Advertisers to learn more about their privacy policies and what options (if any) they offer to opt out of their data collection and use, please follow these links to their Web sites: Six Apart Ltd.   
[http://www.sixapart.com/privacy](http://www.sixapart.com/privacy/) Six Apart Media third party advertising networks and advertisers   
[http://www.sixapart.com/advertising/solutions-for-bloggers/privacy/3rd-party-list/index.html](http://www.sixapart.com/advertising/solutions-for-bloggers/privacy/3rd-party-list/index.html) Some of these third party advertising networks are participants in the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"), a cooperative of online marketing and analytics companies committed to building consumer awareness and establishing responsible business and data management practices and standards. You can learn more about NAI and how you may "opt out" of targeted advertising delivered by NAI member ad networks [here.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

**BuySellAds.com**

BuySellAds.com as a third party vendor serves ads on anshuldudeja.com/anshuldudeja.blogspot.com. BuySellAds.com may use cookies and/or web beacons to gather non-personally identifiable information for statistical purposes.For more information about BuySellAds.com please visit the following pages:Website: [http://buysellads.com/](http://buysellads.com/)  
Privacy Policy: [http://buysellads.com/about/privacy](http://buysellads.com/about/privacy)  
Terms of use: [http://buysellads.com/about/terms](http://buysellads.com/about/terms)

**Third Party Advertisers - General Information** ****

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on anshuldudeja.com/anshuldudeja.blogspot.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see. 

**Anshuldudeja.com/anshuldudeja.blogspot.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.**

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. anshuldudeja.com's/anshuldudeja.blogspot.com's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

"These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on anshuldudeja.blogspot.com/www.anshuldudeja.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies  ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see. 

anshuldudeja.blogspot.com/www.anshuldudeja.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. 

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. anshuldudeja.blogspot.com's/www.anshuldudeja.com's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. 

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites."

**Persistant cookies for site performance**

**Web beacons.** Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns. **Social buttons.** On many of the pages of the site you will see ‘social buttons’. These enable users to share or bookmark the web pages. There are buttons for: Twitter, Google +1, Facebook ‘Like’, LinkedIn ‘Share’, and StumbleUpon. In order to implement these buttons, and connect them to the relevant social networks and external sites, there are scripts from domains outside of Econsultancy. You should be aware that these sites are likely to be collecting information about what you are doing all around the internet, including on Econsultancy’s site. So if you click on any of these buttons, these sites will be registering that action and may use that information. In some cases these sites will be registering the fact that you are visiting Econsultancy, and the specific pages you are on, even if you don’t click on the button if you are logged into their services, like Google and Facebook. You should check the respective policies of each of these sites to see how exactly they use your information and to find out how to opt out, or delete, such information. **External web services.** We use a number of external web services on the Econsultancy site, mostly to display content within our web pages. For example, to display images we often use Flickr; to display slideshows we sometimes use SlideShare; to show videos we use Vimeo and YouTube. This is not an exhaustive or complete list of the services we use, or might use in the future, when embedding content, but these are the most common. As with the social buttons we cannot prevent these sites, or external domains, from collecting information on your usage of this embedded content. If you are not logged in to these external services then they will not know who you are but are likely to gather anonymous usage information e.g. number of views, plays, loads etc.If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites.
